# Muzhe Wu

J 734-358-7357 | ► henrw@umich.edu | ★ henrw.github.io 
G github.com/henrw | ★ @MuzheW | In linkedin.com/in/muzhe-wu-573920223/

### **RESEARCH INTEREST**

My research interest is in the intersection of artificial intelligence and human-computer interaction. I am specifically interested in creating interpretable and generalizable intelligent systems/agents that can learn from humans' behaviors and respond in alignment with humans' intents.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2021 - Apr 2023 (Expected)

• Advisors: Anhong Guo, Xu Wang, Veronica Perez-Rosas

• GPA: 3.95/4.00

# **Shanghai Jiao Tong University**

Shanghai, China

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Sept 2019 - Aug 2023 (Expected)

• GPA: 3.76/4.00 (ranked 21th out of 252 students in the class)

### **PUBLICATIONS, PRESENTATIONS & POSTERS**

2022 <u>Muzhe Wu</u>\*, Haocheng Ren\*, Gregory Croisdale, Xu Wang, Anhong Guo. "Rubikon: A Multimodal Tutor for 3D Physical Task Learning." *Michigan Al Symposium 2022.* Poster Presentation & Demo. [Best Demo Award]

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### Towards Understanding the Relation between Misinformation and Engagement | NLP

Jul 2022 - Present

LIT Lab (UMich) - Advisor: Veronica Perez-Rosas

- Designed a highly interpretable pipeline for online video engagement rating consisting of multimodal (visual, audio and textual) data preprocessing, mid-level feature extraction, time alignment, and an unbalanced early fusion model;
- Formally defined and labeled the engagement rate for the YouTube Prostate Cancer Dataset of 250 videos; trained the pipeline and performed a comparative study on the relation between misinformation and engagement.

**MineDojo** | RL Jul 2022 - Oct 2022

Jim-Team (NVIDIA) - Advisor: Jim Fan

- Enabled GPU acceleration for scalable MineDojo RL simulation on headless machines by investigating EGL docker image;
- Created a meta-dataset of 20 open-ended, task-oriented datasets; scraped web data (e.g., GitHub repos for front-end development frameworks, DALL-E-2 showcase) to construct knowledge bases for generalist agent training.

### **Multimodal Cognitive Tutor | HCI**

May 2022 - Present

HAIL Lab, Lifelong Learning Lab (UMich) - Advised by Xu Wang, Anhong Guo

- Designed a new ITS framework that leverages AI and AR and augments current tutorial methods for physical 3D tasks;
- Build the system for the Rubik's Cube learning, featuring domain/user modeling (by parsing and analyzing multimodal input, e.g., finger detection and ArUco markers), adaptive feedback (based on the abstractive knowledge tree and user/system initiatives), new task generation and low cognitive load guidance (voice aid, hidden side revelation, and spatial arrow).

#### **AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS**

2021, 2022 **Dean's Honor List** at the University of Michigan

2021 Mathematical Contest in Modeling Meritorious Winner Prize (<9.5%)

2020 University Physics Competition Silver Award (<3%)

2019, 2020 **Undergraduate Excellent Scholarship** at Shanghai Jiao Tong University (<10%)

#### **SELECTED PROJECTS**

#### **Auxiliary Variables Improve Group Accuracy without Group Information** [Link]

Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

- Validated the effectiveness of auxiliary variables in the first stage of the JTT algorithm resolving the spurious correlation in ML;
- Designed, recreated, and collected visual datasets for spurious correlation research (e.g., configurable MNIST-CIFAR10).

#### **FAD: Feature Alignment Discriminator for Text Summarization** [Link]

Mar 2022 - Apr 2022

- Introduced a BERT-based discriminator to BART text generator and designed feature alignment mechanism; achieved SOTA
  performance on CNN/DailyMail dataset for automatic abstractive text summarization.
- Trained the model with different settings (rDrop, layers used as features, and hyper-parameters) and compared it with baseline models (e.g., fine-tuned BART-base model) on ROUGE score.

### **Retro Game API for Reinforcement Learning** [Link]

Feb 2022

- Developed an API for retro game simulation with reinforcement learning focus.
- Applied *gym-retro* integration tools to build runnable ROMs; designed a simulation environment with regulation methods and compatible utility classes (recorder, interactor, and dataset); designed a simulation GUI with observation and state information visualized; implemented wrapper classes for vision transform (random cropping, random convolution, and gaussian noise).

### Mask Distribution Simulator [Link]

Jul 2020 - Aug 2020

- Created a C++ program that evaluates the number of masks needed by cities in Hubei Province during the COVID-19 period and simulated the transportation of masks within the province along with subsequent impacts on pandemic situations.
- Applied the SIR model to classify people into different groups; set up parameters per factors including mask numbers and social distance; designed an interactive GUI that displays simulation results with OpenGL.

#### **COMPETITIONS**

#### Mathematical Contest in Modeling | Meritorious Winner Prize

Feb 2021

- Modeled an ecosystem of different types of fungi (competitive relationships) with limited nutrients and simulated their long-term growth trends in various weather conditions.
- Applied Competitive Lotka Volterra Equations to formulate differential equations of fungi's growth; formulated correlation
  factors with geometry and necessary simplifications; evaluated weather factors with linear regression method; visualized
  simulation results in diagrams with MATLAB and Python.

### **University Physics Competition** | Silver Medal

Nov 2020

- Formulated the route for a lightweight spacecraft traveling from earth to Saturn at the minimum fuel cost.
- Applied physics models, e.g., Conservation of Momentum, Kepler's Law, and Hohmann Transfer Orbit, to calculate the optimal track; established the relationships between fuel consumption and weight, distance, and time with Euler's Method.

### **SKILLS & RELATED COURSES**

**SKILLS** 

**Languages** Python, C/C++, Java, Javascript, SQL, C#, MATLAB, R, Verilog **Frameworks** PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, SwiftUI, React, Vue, Scrapy, Flask, Bootstrap

Tools ETFX, Unity, Mathematica, HTML, Figma, Linux (Ubuntu), Solidworks, Adobe Creative Suite

**RELATED COURSES** 

ML/NLP/CV Machine Learning; Natural Language Processing; Computer Vision; Science of Deep Learning;

User Interface Development; Human-Centered ML; Mind & Machine;

**Other CS** Web Systems; Operating Systems; Computer Organization; Data Structures & Algorithms;

Computer Security; Computer Science Foundations & Pragmatics;

Math Multivariable & Vector Calculus; Linear Algebra; Differential Equations; Discrete Math; Probability & Statistics;

**EE** Electrical Circuits; Signals & Systems; Logic Design; Analog Circuits;

#### **VOLUNTEER & EXTRACURRICULAR EXPERIENCE**

# **Ann Arbor Figure Skating Club**

June 2022 - Present

Competed and volunteered in adult figure skating competitions in Ann Arbor.

# SJTU Basketball Association

Aug 2020 – Aug 2021

Organized and refereed in collegial basketball matches at Shanghai Jiao Tong University.

# **High School Advisory**

May 2020

Advised on the College Entrance Examination preparation for ( $\approx$ 700) senior students in Wenzhou No. 2 Foreign Language School.

### **UMJI Voluntary Association**

Oct 2019 - Aug 2020

Regularly visited Jiangchuan Sunshine nursing house, hosting events and caring for people with mental difficulties.

### **REFERENCES**

Anhong Guo
Assistant Professor
Department of CSE
University of Michigan

⊠ anhong@umich.edu (personal website) Xu Wang

Linxi "Jim" Fan

Research Scientist
Al Research
NVIDIA

☑ linxif@nvidia.com
(personal website)

Verónica Pérez-Rosas